Flavio Neubauer - Senior Software Engineer

Email: flavio.neubauer@gmail.com

São Paulo - Brazil

Summary

Experienced software engineer with an 12-year track record of designing and building robust applications. My expertise spans a wide array of technologies, including Java (versions 8 to 17), and a variety of frameworks such as Spring, JSF, Struts, and more recently, Quarkus. I've also excelled in the world of web development, transitioning from AngularJS to Angular 2+ and employing Ionic for Hybrid mobile app creation.

In the realm of DevOps, I'm a fervent advocate for automation, consistently implementing CI/CD practices to elevate project efficiency. My toolkit includes Gitlab CI, Jenkins, Shell Scripting, Docker, and Kubernetes.

My passion extends to documentation, where I consider code and diagrams as vital forms of communication. My favorite tools for this purpose are Markdown and the C4 model, ensuring clarity and coherence in project documentation.

Experience

Perinity - Senior Software Engineer - 10/2018 - present

Governance, risk, audit, and compliance enterprise application system delivered as SAAS.

- worked on security issues to overcome pen-tests appointments of a legacy application, which unblocked ten new contracts
- designed a modernization process of the product using the strangler pattern of the legacy monolith and DDD to separate domains and teams, creating four teams and services for each team
- Containerization and continuous integration of all services using docker multi-stage, Gitlab CI, and Container registry that automated 100% of the deployment to stage environments
- created a system using Kubernetes, Java with Quarkus, Angular, Postgres, and cloud tools like AWS Route53 and S3 to help the QA team create test environments within a single form

Murah IT - Senior Software Engineer - 11/2015 - 09/2018

Software House with solutions in the area of electronic document management and auditing.

- created a multi-tenant auditing system in less than six months using Spring Boot, Angular JS, and Postgres providing MVP features like auditing and questionnaire, checklist answers, reports, dashboard, and payment integration
- improved a critical system of a great national bank, changing the architecture to separate image upload from document metadata which caused a significant impact on user experience and performance using Angular JS and Java
- developed a hybrid frontend application using Ionic to integrate with a system used by more than 500 drugstores

Rede Ponto Certo - Software Engineer 03/2014 - 08/2015

Kiosk builder who provided metro card recharge at metro stations using credit cards and paper money.

- contributed to designing an IOT application to monitor kiosk applications and money detection equipment that helped identify scams
- integrated the kiosk Java application with monitoring backend using JNDI as a bridge to a C++ library
- developed the system to receive equipment status of more than 400 hundred kiosks using C++, Oracle Database, PHP, HTML 5, and CSS3

Yellow-Green Technologies - Software Engineer 2011 - 02/2014

Traffic enforcement system builder with more than 20 cities as clients in different states of Brazil.

- worked building server side for traffic enforcement system, processing 750k images monthly on a single C++ instance
- pair programming to help create the traffic enforcement client application that had more monitored lanes, panoramic cams, Linux compatibility, and more control from the server side
- created a web application using PHP, HTML 5, and CSS3 to configure client application parameters that saved at least 1 fieldwork day for each piece of equipment during the installation period

Education

FIAP

Software Architecture · (2023 - present)

FIAP

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Project Management · (2011 - 2013)

Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electrician · (2005 - 2010)

Skillset

Backend: Java 8 - 17 | Spring | Quarkus | JSF

Frontend: HTML5 | CSS3 | Angular JS | Angular 2+

Operational Systems: Mac OS | Linux

Devops: Git | Shell Script | Gitlab CI | Jenkins | Docker | Kubernetes

Diagraming: C4 and Mermaid JS

Cloud: AWS | OCI | Azure

Databases: Postgres | Oracle | MongoDB